# **Gabriel Queiroz**

Software Developer

Vancouver, BC — Canada

+1 (236) 986 6277 — gabriel.fatec@hotmail.com



## **ABOUT ME**

Technologist graduated on System Analysis and Development at Technology College (Brazil, São Paulo) with extension bachelor degree in Computer Science at University of New Orleans (USA, Louisiana). Software Developer since 2011 have been working in technology area for more than six years. Recent works involves the development of RESTful APIs, Microservices-based applications and Event Sourcing, following Domain Driven Design standards.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# • **Software Developer at Traction Guest** — (Ago 2018 - Present)

Worked on the Backend applications, participating in the development of new features using Ruby on Rails, and microservices using Golang also helping with production incidents and chores. Focused on refactoring the current state of the application, improving the performance and code quality for new and already existing features.

Helped and coordinated DevOps activites, such as: Dockerize current backend applications; Manage applications on Cloud Services using Heroku, Amazon, GCP and Cloud66; Manage CI/CD integration with Codeship and Codefresh; Manage PostgresSQL updates and backups; Manage application monitoring using NewRelic, Librato and Sentry.

# • Software Developer at Wirecard Brasil — (Feb 2016 - Jun 2018)

Worked on financial products solutions, such as balance, statement, transfer, and others, participating in the development of RESTful APIs, microservices-based applications, following domain driven design standards with continuous integration and continuous deployment.

Developing highly distributed applications mostly in Java (mainly using Spring boot), Ruby (on Rails, Sinatra and Grape), and Kotlin. Also worked on financial reports using ElasticSearch and asynchronous services using RabbitMQ. Had the opportunity to implement Event Sourcing using Apache Kafka working with stream processors and connectors. Managed cloud applications with

Amazon Elastic Container Service and Amazon EC2 for instances and load balancers. Continuous integration and continuous deployment using Jenkins and CircleCI.

# • Unity Developer at University of New Orleans — (Jan 2015 - May 2015)

Part of the academic software development team at the University of New Orleans (Louisiana, USA) as Unity developer, using Unity 5.1 with Javascript and C#. Direct interaction on all stages of software development such as: Software requirement specification; Software modeling and prototyping; Validation of requirements based on the development of application modules.

### **EDUCATION**

# • System Analysis and Development at Technology College — Sao Paulo. SP, BRA (2011 - 2015)

During my graduation it was required knowledge at different stages of software development, such as requirements gathering, software modeling and design with an emphasis on UML standards, persistence modeling for relational databases, software quality with unity and integration tests.

# • Extension on Computer Science at University Of New Orleans — New Orleans. LA, EUA (2014 - 2015)

Brazil Scientific Mobility Program, fully funded scholarship recipient as an undergraduate student in Computer Science at the University of New Orleans. As part of my studies I had the opportunity to take classes of mobile development, artificial intelligence, analysis of algorithm, game design and other classes. As result of my performance I was invited to join the Narrative Intelligence Lab team and work on a machine learning project for the local schools.

#### SKILLS

- · Design scalable, robust and resilient software architecture;
- · Development processes on Agile, Scrum and Kanban;
- Version Control using Github and BitBucket;
- Continuous integration tools such as Jenkins, CircleCl, Codeship and Codefresh;
- Database SQL such as MySQL, PostgreSQL and NoSQL such as Redis, MongoDB;
- · Search-engine tools such as ElasticSearch;
- Event Sourcing and Messaging using Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, Sidekiq and Resque.
- Application Monitoring using New Relic and AWS Cloud Watch.
- Container orchestration using Amazon Elastic Container Service.

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Portuguese Native language.
- English Full professional proficiency.
- **Spanish** Elementary proficiency.
- **Japanese** Basic writing and reading (Hiragana and Katakana).

#### **CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES**

- Tests of Java Softwares Universidade de São Paulo, 30h, 2016.
- Android Development Samsung Ocean, 8h, 2015.
- JavaScript Fundamentals SoloLearn, 2015.
- Java Course SoloLearn, 2015.

#### **ARTICLES AND TALKS**

- VanRuby Lightning Talks: Intro to RCurtain (EN) Youtube, 2018 (EN).
- What is this Apache Kafka? Medium, 2017 (PT-BR).
- Let's talk about Event Sourcing Medium, 2017 (PT-BR).
- How to use Kafka JDBC Sink Connector Medium, 2017 (PT-BR).
- IFMAN your super-hero for Features and A/B testing Medium, 2017 (PT-BR).

#### **ACADEMIC REFERENCES**

• University Of New Orleans — Reading Rocket.

Developed at the University of New Orleans (Louisiana, USA), it aims to assist the process of assessing the reading level of high school students in the state of Louisiana in an interactive and easy way. The game purpose is determine reading level of a student by the data obtained while the student plays the game using data mining.

• **Technology College** — Collaborative Tool for Students and Teachers.

End of course work of the Systems Analysis and Development course at FATEC, aims to help students during their academic journey, providing a collaborative tool for students and teachers, allowing a quick and practical interaction. Open Source tool that can be easily adapted to other schools and universities using its own android application or any other systems consumes RESTful APIs. Developed Android Application, Web Service and MySQL Database on cloud.